

CONTACT



(55) 1953-9570



chech.alvarez@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Self-taught attitude
- Willingness to relocate
- Teamwork
- Strong communication skills
- Responsible
- Adaptability

EDUCATION

- Computer Systems
 Engineering
 UNITEC
- Diploma in Organizational Psychology
 UNITEC

Sergio Álvarez Mendizábal

ABOUT ME

I started my adventure as a developer in 2011 this is when I fell in love with this profession by working together with very passionate people. My adventure continues now with more than 10 years of experience like freelance, working in large and small companies and startups, developing skills such as project management and negotiation.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Terramar Brands

Web and mobile application developer. 2013 - Present

I continuously improve the web and mobile app user's experience by searching for new technologies.

After the mobile app code was managed externally I implemented the management internally which reduced costs and allowed the brand to have full control of the design and the code.

Not only I led the México web and app projects, I also developed and led the USA eCommerce and mobile app. I also developed the mobile application used for international trips.

I continuously migrate all my API REST and web development work to AWS from the company servers.

Redcube

Fullstack developer. Nov 2016 - Aug 2020

I developed with my team the Wilson Sports Mx eCommerce with our own code. I also contributed to the creation of a tool that any person without programming skills could create their own personalized eCommerce.

COMPETENCIES

FRONT

Javascript, React, Next, Vite, Vue, PHP, CSS, Tailwind

BACK

NodeJS, PHP, .NET

MOBILE

React Native

DB & API

MongoDB, SQL, MySQL, Firebase, GraphQL

BUILD

Docker, Kubernetes, Apache, Nginx

AWS

Amplify, S3, EKS, ECS, EC2, Lambda, CloudFront, Route 53, IAM, API Gateway

LANGUAGES

SPANISH

Native

ENGLISH

Intermediate

DGL Latam

Fullstack developer.

Mar 2014 - Nov 2016

With the Magento platform I developed the eCommerce web page.

I connected the Walmart API REST with our admin backoffice for supply chain communication purposes.

Telmex

Fullstack developer.

Oct 2012 - Mar 2013

I managed the backend and front-end maintenance according to administrative requests.

SIDE PROJECTS

Serpa Cloud

Front-end developer.

Aug 2022 - Present

I program the requested views and solve errors reported by the QA team.

Buró parlamentario

React Native developer.

Mar 2021 - Jul 2022

I programmed the mobile application front-end for the Colombian government "InfoCandidato". The senate and presidency candidates could interact with the colombian citizens in a more friendly way. My observations and communication improved the user's experience.